CONTACT

WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/TINA-K-WORDEN TK.WORDEN@GMAIL.COM

PROJECT MANAGER

WORDEN

TINA

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a highly skilled Project and Program Manager supporting non-profit programs and the Department of Defense. As a self-employed business leader with over 10 years of corporate experience leading a small technology company in federal contracts, my entrepreneurial approach has earned the trust and recognition on federal contracts and in my community. I continue to leverage and develop my skills to stay current with industry trends and serve in leadership roles that contribute to the success of organizations that focus on my interests in business and the arts.

EDUCATION

MA Education and Human Development The George Washington University | Washington, DC

BA International Studies

George Mason University | Fairfax, Virginia

Software Engineering Cohort

Per Scholas | Silver Spring, Maryland

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional - PMP September 2022

Defense Information Security Service Facility Security Officer, 2015

Real Estate Brokers License (Virginia)March 2012

Professional Teaching Licensure Virginia, 1998

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Technical Writer
- Stakeholder Management
- JavaScript/CSS/HTML
- Full Stack Web Development
- MongoDB/Express/React/Node.js
- Strategic Planning
- CRM Database Systems
- Communications Management
- Microsoft and MacOS Office Suite
- Grants Management
- Partnership Development
- Relationship Building
- Marketing/Graphic Design
- PM Software
- Collaboration Software

EXPERIENCE

PRESIDENT/PROGRAM MANAGER

WTS LLC JANUARY 2011 - Present

- Provided professional modernization solutions to US Navy executives and senior level civilians to secure critical Navy applications into the AWS GovCloud.
 - Created strategic infrastructure solutions, executive summaries, and regular status reports for program leadership
 - Strategized with key personnel to assess and prioritize emerging AWS relationships on behalf of the Navy to adopt and integrate AWS GovCloud
 - Directed and strategized with SMEs to customize unique approaches to modernize over 250 critical applications for support in the AWS GovCloud
- Result: The Navy was able to ensure enterprise-level system compliance by centralizing and scaling licenses resulting in the significant reduction of human and financial resources

VICE PRESIDENT

Arlington County Civic Federation

JUNE 2020 - JUNE 2021

- Researched, identified, negotiated, and integrated a video teleconference capability to keep the community safe while staying informed during the global pandemic
- Supported over 400 Civic Federation members to address important local and state issues and use our collective voice to impact the discourse in Arlington Developed standards and ensured compliance with corporate bylaws
- Created a strategic communication plan to improve membership and community engagement
- Facilitated the completion of a comprehensive financial audit

BOARD OF DIRECTORS

Museum of Contemporary Art Arlington JUNE 2021 - Present

- Provide oversight and support of the nonprofit's strategic and business plans
- Leverage professional expertise towards expanding organizational capabilities
- Secure resources for general operating support and programs and on a local, regional, and national level

FELLOW

Per Scholas Software Engineering Cohort JULY 2022 – NOVEMBER 2022

- Developed over 20+ software and web applications, websites, and databases
- Developed and executed Major Projects using different programming languages and frameworks for back-end and front-end servers
- Participated in an intensive 15-week fellowship that included in-class instruction and individual and group projects